<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supervisions on Henrik Røed Sherling</title>
    <link>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supervisions on Henrik Røed Sherling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part IB Knowledge, Language, and World</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/klw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/klw/</guid>
      <description>Back to all supervision subjects.
Here are the topics, questions, and reading lists for the Part IB Knowledge, Language, and World supervisions in the Philosophy Tripos at Cambridge. Students must choose just one question per week when more than one is listed.
1 Modality Questions:
What would it mean for modality to be a fiction? &amp;lsquo;When I say that Hilary Clinton might have won, I mean that she might have won, not that someone like her might have won.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part IB Ethics</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/ethics/</guid>
      <description>Back to all supervision subjects.
Here are the topics, questions, and reading lists for the Part IB Ethics supervisions in the Philosophy Tripos at Cambridge. Students must choose just one question when more than one is listed. Only four topics will be covered.
1 Practical reason Questions:
‘If people’s reasons for action depend on their desires, then people without at least some desire to be good have no reason to be good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part IB History of Analytic Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/hap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/hap/</guid>
      <description>Back to all supervision subjects.
Here are the topics, questions, and reading lists for the Part IB History of Analytic Philosophy supervisions in the Philosophy Tripos at Cambridge. Students must choose just one question per week when more than one is listed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part II Philosophy of Mind</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/pom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/pom/</guid>
      <description>Back to all supervision subjects.
Here are the topics, questions, and reading lists for the Part II Philosophy of Mind supervisions in the Philosophy Tripos at Cambridge. Students must choose just one question when more than one is listed. Only four topics will be covered.
1 Intentionality Question:
&amp;lsquo;Thermostats really have beliefs and desires.&amp;rsquo; Discuss.
Required reading:
Dennett, &amp;lsquo;Intentional systems&amp;rsquo;. Searle, &amp;lsquo;Minds, Brains, and Computers&amp;rsquo;. Haugeland, &amp;lsquo;Understanding: Dennett and Searle&amp;rsquo;. 2 Consciousness Question:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part II Wittgenstein and His Successors</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/wah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/wah/</guid>
      <description>Back to all supervision subjects.
Here are the topics, questions, and reading lists for the Part II Wittgenstein and His Successors supervisions in the Philosophy Tripos at Cambridge. Students must choose just one question per week on a new topic and at least one topic from each philosopher.
1 Austin ‘But if we are prepared to admit that there may be… some cases in which “delusive and veridical perceptions” really are indistinguishable, does this admission require us to drag in, or even let in sense-data?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy of Economics</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/poe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/poe/</guid>
      <description>Back to all supervision subjects.
This paper is with HPS. As such, there is a standardised supervision guide for all students, which can be found either by asking your supervisor or by consulting Moodle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy of Science</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/pos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/teaching/supervisions/pos/</guid>
      <description>Back to all supervision subjects.
Here are the topics, questions, and reading lists for the Part II Philosophy of Science supervisions in the Philosophy Tripos at Cambridge. Students must choose just one question when more than one is listed. Only four topics will be covered.
1 Biology Question:
How, if at all, can stating the function of a feature of an organism explain that feature?
Primary reading:
Millikan, &amp;lsquo;In defense of proper functions&amp;rsquo; Neander, &amp;lsquo;Functions as Selected Effects: The Conceptual Analyst&amp;rsquo;s Defense&amp;rsquo; Godfrey-Smith, &amp;lsquo;A modern history theory of functions&amp;rsquo; Garson, &amp;lsquo;Function and Teleology&amp;rsquo; Secondary reading:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
