<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Henrik Sherling</title>
    <link>https://hsherl.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Henrik Sherling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hsherl.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading Bohm 1</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/02/26/reading-bohm-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/02/26/reading-bohm-1/</guid>
      <description>David Bohm was a strange character whose strangeness has been skimmed off the way his works are now presented. He was not just the theorist of the de Broglie-Bohm pilot-wave, hidden variables interpretation of Quantum Mechanics. (If unclear: this is a silly test post to make sure things look and work all right on the website!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can reach me at hsherling @ gmail dot com or come to my office hours any Monday or Wednesday from 16:00 to 17:00 (GMT+00) — if I’m not there, I’ll pop in as soon as I see the email notification that you have joined. I am on Twitter too, though I don’t check it very often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here are some things I have worked on lately:
 Refereed philosophy papers for Dialexicon Journal Translated English psychology articles to Norwegian for Practical Health Psychology At King’s College London:  Presented a paper for the PsychSoc journal club Co-organized Philosophy of Mental Disorder Discussion Group with PhilSoc and PsychSoc Co-organized Epistemology of Peer Disagreement Reading Group with PhilSoc Co-organized Alexander Bogdanov Reading Group with PhilSoc Co-wrote Dark Matter and Dark Energy Lecture Notes (2019-2020) 7CCP4935   For St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumé</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>I am currently on the lookout for a job. You can find my work experience and education below. Get in touch if you are interested in working with me. PDF version of my resumé is available here. Last updated: November 15th, 2020.
Work experience Product Analyst, curalens.ai (2020-) I analysed therapy transcripts and thence made testing data and classifiers for a machine learning algorithm that will perform mental health assessments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
