<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Henrik Sherling</title>
    <link>https://hsherl.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Henrik Sherling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hsherl.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Snark Web</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/06/21/intellectual-snark-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/06/21/intellectual-snark-web/</guid>
      <description>Sam Harris (on episode #243 of his podcast Making Sense): “Many people are confused about some of the views I express on this podcast … I get the sense that many Making Sense listeners don’t know where I’m coming from”. A remarkable confession that he is not living up to his own title. “There are certain things I actually understand about my own mind and about the mind in general—and the idea that racial identity is something we can’t get past is total bullshit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can the arrow of time be conventional?</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/03/01/can-the-arrow-of-time-be-conventional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/03/01/can-the-arrow-of-time-be-conventional/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Smolin’s Multiverse and Peirce’s Synechism</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/03/01/on-smolins-multiverse-and-peirces-synechism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/03/01/on-smolins-multiverse-and-peirces-synechism/</guid>
      <description>Lee Smolin has argued for an altogether different kind of multiverse than the one we see in popular science. The hypothesis is that the laws of nature themselves have evolved through a natural selection of universes, of which there were many, and of which there is now (at least) our universe. Stable tendencies in the universes are preferred by the selection process, just like they are in evolution within each universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vanquished Foes of The Metal; or, The Aesthetic of Anger</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/03/01/the-vanquished-foes-of-the-metal-or-the-aesthetic-of-anger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/03/01/the-vanquished-foes-of-the-metal-or-the-aesthetic-of-anger/</guid>
      <description>Metal by Tenacious D: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qR7U1HIhxfA
Jörg Scheller describes in his 2020 book, Metalmorphoses: The Unlikely Changes of Heavy Metal (Metalmorphosen: Die unwahrscheinlichen Wandlungen des Heavy Metal
The disaster of the calmness thesis of Metal (https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4439552/ ; https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fnhum.2015.00272/full)
Rant to Ariel: I was listening to Metallica the other day in the car and I had an idea for an essay or somethign
it made me think like what if I could get an interview with James Hetfield, hahaha</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference and the History of Emergence</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/02/27/difference-and-the-history-of-emergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/02/27/difference-and-the-history-of-emergence/</guid>
      <description>How can the same carved piece of wood be a rook one day and yet be a mere carved piece of wood the day before? Something — someone, the chess players — in between makes the piece play the role as a rook. But what about the chess players themselves? What makes them able to make carved pieces of wood into chess pieces?
I am now merely a Norwegian citizen. But I am soon to be a British citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Bohm 1</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/02/26/reading-bohm-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/2021/02/26/reading-bohm-1/</guid>
      <description>David Bohm was a strange character whose strangeness has been skimmed off the way his works are now presented. He was not just the theorist of the de Broglie-Bohm pilot-wave, hidden variables interpretation of Quantum Mechanics. (If unclear: this is a silly test post to make sure things look and work all right on the website!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can reach me at hsherling @ gmail dot com or book a meeting with me through Calendly. I am on Twitter too, though I don’t check it very often!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Sunset at Storavatnet.
Here are some things I have worked on lately:
 At King’s College London:  I co-organized reading groups with the Philosophy Society about the philosophy of mental disorder (joint with the Psychiatry Society), the epistemology of peer disagreement, and the philosophy of Alexander Bogdanov. I co-wrote the class materials for a graduate class in physics about Dark Matter and Dark Energy (7CCP4935). I presented a cohort study by Brown et.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumé</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>I am currently on the lookout for a job. You can find my work experience and education below. Get in touch if you are interested in working with me. PDF version of my resumé is available here. Last updated: November 15th, 2020.
Work experience Product Analyst, curalens.ai (2020-) I analysed therapy transcripts and thence made testing data and classifiers for a machine learning algorithm that will perform mental health assessments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should we care whether we are different?</title>
      <link>https://hsherl.github.io/1/01/01/should-we-care-whether-we-are-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsherl.github.io/1/01/01/should-we-care-whether-we-are-different/</guid>
      <description>Crispin Sartwell wrote a scathing criticism in The New York Times of the tendency among Western Philosophers to search for a difference between animals and humans. Why is it so important to them that and how humans are different to squirrels? As he says: “if we truly believed we were so much better than squirrels, why have we spent thousands of years driving home the point?”
The obvious answer is that it matters to humans to know ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
